<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>learning on </title>
    <link>/categories/learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in learning on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Contributing to Open Source</title>
      <link>/post/2018-03-09-contributing-to-open-source/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-03-09-contributing-to-open-source/</guid>
      <description>You probably use open source software if you are programmer and you know you should probably at some point give back right? I&#39;ve been programming since I was a kid and working as a professional programmer for 17 years (at the time of this post). I freaking love code but I wouldn&#39;t say I&#39;ve contributed a lot in the past years. :(
I want to talk about some of my experiences and what you can do to get started.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Arrays Part 5</title>
      <link>/post/2014-08-28-exploring-arrays-part-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2014-08-28-exploring-arrays-part-5/</guid>
      <description>BTW Going to use Ruby 2.1.2 from here on out
Yes, it has been awhile but (who has time to dwell on the past?) I haven&#39;t forgotten I was going through each array class! My last post said next was delete, so let&#39;s get to it!
delete delete(obj) → item or nil delete(obj) { block } → item or result of block  Ok first one looks pretty straight forward, it returns item if it found it and nil if it doesn&#39;t.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Arrays - Part 2</title>
      <link>/post/2013-03-11-exploring-arrays-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2013-03-11-exploring-arrays-part-2/</guid>
      <description>My second blog post on the topic. Between the writings of this post and part 1 Ruby 2.0 was released on its 20th birthday! But I am going to stick with Ruby 1.9.3 for this series, maybe after I am done I&#39;ll see what changed for 2.0
Array Documentation http://ruby-doc.org/core-1.9.3/Array.html
BTW, to make an array you can use the %w and space separated list of values, I will use that here to save on typing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Arrays - Part 1</title>
      <link>/post/2013-02-23-exploring-arrays-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2013-02-23-exploring-arrays-part-1/</guid>
      <description>Everytime that I have to lookup something with hashes or arrays, I find lots of methods that I didn&#39;t know about, so I thought I&#39;d do an experiment where I will learn about each one and write some examples and try to understand how to use it. I kind of picture someone sitting next to me as I do this, reading the docs and trying them out with me.
Ruby 1.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>