<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>automation on </title>
    <link>/categories/automation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in automation on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/automation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Automation - What to test?</title>
      <link>/post/2018-07-22-browser-automation-what-to-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-07-22-browser-automation-what-to-test/</guid>
      <description>Recently I&#39;ve been working with a QA team and I&#39;ve learned how to test the browser from them and have came up with some of my own ideas learning from Trial and Error. I have spent close to 1.5 years doing Automation Testing whereas previously I&#39;ve always been a test obsessed developer with little in the way of browser testing.
This post is focusing on testing the browser and automating the tests.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting Up Jenkins For Robot Framework</title>
      <link>/post/2018-04-09-setting-up-jenkins-for-robot-framework/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-04-09-setting-up-jenkins-for-robot-framework/</guid>
      <description>Robot framework is a test automation framework. There are many uses for it, but I use it for selenium web testing. But no matter what you test you can use it for many things.
Jenkins a tool to manage &amp;ldquo;jobs&amp;rdquo;, segments of work that you might use &amp;ldquo;cron&amp;rdquo; for.
I use it to run robot framework tests nightly or every 6 hours, or whatever you need.
Jenkins is breeze to set up (at least on mac) and once installed search in the plugins for the robot framework plugin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tagging in Robot Framework</title>
      <link>/post/2017-05-23-tagging-in-robot-framework/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2017-05-23-tagging-in-robot-framework/</guid>
      <description>I talked about the awesome robot framework in the previous post and I wanted to talk about Tagging since I think this is very useful.
Tagging is one way to group tests so you run a subset of tests. In your test case, add this:
Homepage Loads [Tags] smoke Open Homepage Element Should Be Visible ${FIND_LOGO} [Teardown] Close Browser Results to run just one tag:
▶ robot --include smoke youtube.robot ============================================================================== Youtube :: A test to demo testing YouTube ============================================================================== Homepage Loads | PASS | ------------------------------------------------------------------------------ Search Loads Results | PASS | ------------------------------------------------------------------------------ Youtube :: A test to demo testing YouTube | PASS | 2 critical tests, 2 passed, 0 failed 2 tests total, 2 passed, 0 failed ============================================================================== You can create a focus so it is easy to run that one test as you are developing it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automation Testing with Robot Framework</title>
      <link>/post/2017-05-21-automation-testing-with-robot-framework/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2017-05-21-automation-testing-with-robot-framework/</guid>
      <description>On one of my projects recently, I was tasked with finding an automation framework. Looking at my options..
 Cucumber (ruby, although other languages could be used) Capybara / Rspec (ruby) Robot Framework (python)  All of the options for web testing use either Selenium or Watir. I have only did a little with Watir, so I focused on something with Selenium for my first pass of experimentation.
I love testing if you know anything about me, I&#39;m nuts about testing.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>