<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>career on </title>
    <link>/categories/career/</link>
    <description>Recent content in career on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/career/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>What I Wished I knew</title>
      <link>/post/2017-06-11-what-i-wished-i-knew/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2017-06-11-what-i-wished-i-knew/</guid>
      <description>A few things I wish I knew when I started my career as a software developer.
Go to User Groups! I was working for 2-3 years before I got the courage to go to my first user group. Now I currently run one, and have in the past run more than one. Get out there and meet people, if it is a long commute to the meeting or you have little kids at home (often an excuse/reason I hear) then maybe only go every 2-3 months.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview Prep</title>
      <link>/post/2017-06-06-interview-prep/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2017-06-06-interview-prep/</guid>
      <description>I recently went through this process so I thought it would be good to share what I think are good things to do to prepare for an interview.
Logistics Arrive early, sit in your car or outside and walk in 15 mins before (I&#39;m kind of paranoid, so I get there 30 mins before usually). Ask me about a job I didn&#39;t get (years ago) because I was late. Hey, I had a good reason, they changed the time on me and mentioned it an attachment (not the body of the email) that I didn&#39;t notice was there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading Books Cover-to-Cover</title>
      <link>/post/2013-01-13-reading-books-cover-to-cover/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2013-01-13-reading-books-cover-to-cover/</guid>
      <description>I wanted to buy &amp;ldquo;Practical Object-Orientated Design in Ruby&amp;rdquo; by Sandi Metz when it first came out, and I had a hard time justifying it because there are many books I have bought and have not read all the way through. So I thought I&#39;d do an experiment in reading a tech book cover-to-cover and then I&#39;ll buy &amp;ldquo;poodr&amp;rdquo;. So my first cover-to-cover read was Eloquent Ruby by Russ Olsen. Not all books should be read cover-to-cover but when you read a book cover-to-cover you&#39;ll discover a few things:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>