<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>javascript on </title>
    <link>/categories/javascript/</link>
    <description>Recent content in javascript on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/javascript/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>using jshint</title>
      <link>/post/2017-03-16-using-jshint/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2017-03-16-using-jshint/</guid>
      <description>Javascript. It&#39;s a language that some of us love to hate, me occasionally. Here&#39;s a few notes to myself to make JS a little better :)
Use these settings in JSHint to avoid instanity:
file: .jshintrc { &amp;quot;flagname&amp;quot; : true } If you have settings that apply to only your test environment you can put those in test/.jshintrc (maybe allowing global var for your test function) .. you can extend a confiuration in another file with this option `&amp;quot;extends&amp;rdquo; : &amp;ldquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trying out Emberjs Models and views</title>
      <link>/post/2012-09-03-trying-out-emberjs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2012-09-03-trying-out-emberjs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve read about emberjs and I&#39;ve tried &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.codeschool.com/courses/anatomy-of-backbonejs&#34;&gt;CodeSchool Backbone&lt;/a&gt; and the concepts are interesting, I like the concept of a model updating some text on the screen without having to write $(&#39;#myelement&amp;rsquo;).text(&amp;lsquo;updated content&amp;rsquo;) and a friend was mentioning how much they like the emberjs models. So, I wanted to try and in a way I could only worry about a few pieces (that router and junk still kinda makes me crazy for frontend since I do that on the back end.. maybe I just need to do more). I was reading the &lt;a href=&#34;http://emberjs.com/documentation/&#34;&gt;Ember Documentation&lt;/a&gt; and they have some small examples that inspired me. So I set out to try somethings:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I downloaded the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/downloads/emberjs/starter-kit/starter-kit.1.0.pre.zip&#34;&gt;Starter Kit&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.emberjs.com&#34;&gt;emberjs.com&lt;/a&gt; and it had a skeleton index and app.js file ready to go. Nice. I first played around with making a model and calling a method on it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a Image Gallery in jQuery</title>
      <link>/post/2011-01-23-creating-a-image-gallery-in-jquery/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2011-01-23-creating-a-image-gallery-in-jquery/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For one of my projects, I wanted to have a link that will open an image gallery in a lightbox. I want thumbnails at the bottom, that would display above the thumbs but larger. I found alot&amp;hellip;alot of them in jquery. I found blogposts that &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;review 30&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; (and &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;and 10&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; and &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;and 15&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; and &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;and 14&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; and there is more!) of them at a time! So, do I try and modify one.. or .. do I write one myself?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was also inspired by &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Garann&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; (fellow DevChix) because she decided to write her &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;own text editor&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; (something I probably wouldn&#39;t attempt&amp;hellip;but she said it was not too bad! so maybe it wouldn&#39;t be that bad after all??)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So simple interface:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clicking the link will open the gallery, looking like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Koan-A-Copia!</title>
      <link>/post/2011-01-22-koan-a-copia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2011-01-22-koan-a-copia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I first learned about Koans from EdgeCase Ruby Koans project, it was great fun and great practice. Since then, whenever I mentored a DevChix or RailsMentors member I suggest to start doing Koans&amp;hellip; even on a regular basis, once you finish them all &amp;hellip; then start over! I always have a ruby koan mid-way and work on it when I want to practice ruby. Sometimes I try to complete the whole file then run it. Since I’ve been learning Groovy this week, I looked to see if there was Groovy Koans, found those.. then I just started compiling all the languages I know of..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ruby&#34;&gt;Ruby&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rubykoans.com&#34;&gt;http://www.rubykoans.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;python&#34;&gt;Python&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gregmalcolm/python_koans&#34;&gt;https://github.com/gregmalcolm/python_koans&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>